Andrew Rosario

Software Engineer and Life-long Learner working with React, Redux, Rails, Ruby, Javascript, HTML5, CSS, and SQL to build amazing things. I love solving difficult problems creatively and collaboratively.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

DIYHelper

https://diyhelper.herokuapp.com/ https://github.com/andrewrosario/home-helper-frontend

DIY Helper is a project to connect DIY Novices and Experts and provide them with a real-time collaboration tool using a React Frontend and Rails REST API backend. Node.js express server websockets allow both users to see live updates from the other as they are made. A progress wheel allows users to track real progress on their project to maintain motivation.

Technologies: React, React Hooks, Javascript, Redux, Rails, Ruby, Node.js, Express Server, Sockets, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS, Auth, Heroku, Amazon S3

Petsmatch

https://petsmatch-frontend.herokuapp.com/

Petsmatch is a dating app for animal lovers. Our motto is: "If your pets don't match you don't match." Built with users in mind, the program uses a two-way matching algorithm that matches users on age, gender, type of pet they have and type of pet they are seeking in others.

Technologies: React, Javascript, Rails, Ruby, Sockets, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS, Heroku, Amazon S3

Lizzbians — A Lizzo Fan Site

https://andrewrosario.github.io/Lizzbians_A-Lizzo-Stan-Page/ https://github.com/andrewrosario/Lizzbians_A-Lizzo-Stan-Page

Created a full-stack application inspired by the musician Lizzo. The application uses a Rails API and PostgreSQL backend and vanilla Javascript frontend to deliver a dynamic, single page experience. The app was created with the mobile experience in mind and is fully responsive.

Technologies: Javascript, Ruby on Rails API, HTML5, CSS3, PostgreSQL, Bootstrap, Heroku, AWS S3

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

Open Source Contributions

- DCAF Case Manager
- Voices of Consent

710 Colorado Unit 3i Austin, TX 78701 (512) 673-9366

rosario.andrew@gmail.com GitHub - andrewrosario

Languages

- Javascript
- Ruby
- HTML5
- CSS
- Relational Databases/SQL

Libraries and Frameworks

- React
- Redux
- Rails
- Sinatra
- TDD RSpec and Mocha

Other Technical Skills

- Bootstrap
- Git/Github
- RESTful Architecture
- Object Oriented Programming
- MVC Architecture

HackOut - LGBTQIA Hackathon

Conceived, researched and developed a web app where consumers were able to identify and purchase clothes and furniture seen on TV over a weekend Hackathon

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Austin ISD, Austin, TX — Asst. Principal

Aug. 2016 - July. 2019

Conducted biannual performance reviews for 70 teachers and provided ongoing feedback and coaching

Designed a system for campus testing, using digital tools to optimize the process and insure appropriate accommodations were provided to students with special needs, and complying with all federal and state laws and regulations

Austin ISD, Austin, TX — Math Instructional Coach

Aug. 2014 - Aug. 2016

Conducted informal teacher observations to improve instructional quality through feedback and mentoring

Led math data analysis teams in ongoing disaggregation of data and the development of specific plans for review and reteach lessons

Austin ISD, Austin, TX — Teacher (Master Math & Special Education)

Aug. 2007 - June 2014

Achieved the highest Texas Education Agency ratings as a Title I school: Exemplary Campus 2009–10, 2010–11, and distinction categories Top 25%, Achievement in Reading/ELA, Achievement in Mathematics; Recognized Campus 2007–08 and 2008–09

EDUCATION

Flatiron School - Software Engineering Immersive Program

Texas State University, San Marcos, TX — *M.Ed. Math Education*

Oakland University, Rochester, MI — B.A. History